The tragedy of McBeth act for, by William Shakespeare.
Drama.
Review and anticipate.
In act 3, McBeth hires murderers to kill Banquo and Banquo's son Fliens.
The murderers botched the job, killing Banquo but allowing Fliens to escape.
Then, at a state banquet, McBeth is shocked to see the ghost of Banquo sitting in the king's chair.
McBeth decides to visit the witches again, determined to know the worst.
At the end of act 3, we learn that Malcolm is in England preparing to invade Scotland,
and that McBeth has gone to join him.
In act 4, McBeth seeks help from the witches to secure his power.
The forces of good, however, are beginning to gather against him.
Scene 1.
A witch's haunt.
Thunder.
Enter the three witches.
Thrice the brim did cat-athmute.
Thrice and once the hedge pig wine.
Harp your cries.
Dis time.
Round about the cold wringo.
In the poisoned entrails throw, toad that under cold stone days and nights.
Has that he won?
Sweltreed venom sleeping got boiled out first either charmed pot.
Double, double, toil and sorrow.
Fire, run and cold run, bubble.
Fill it up a thinny snake in the cauldron boil and bake.
I have knew, then, toe of frog, will of that,
and tongue of dog, adors fork and blind worm sting.
Lizard's leg and howl it's wing for a charm of powerful trouble.
Like a hill-broth boil and bubble.
Double, toil and sorrow.
Fire, burn and cold run, bubble.
Scale of dragon, tooth of wolf, which is mummy, more and gulf of the raven, soapsy shark.
Root of am luck did did the dark.
Liver of blaspheming dew, gall of goat and slips of you,
slivered in the moon's eclipse.
Knows of jerk and tartars lips.
Finger of births, strangled, babed, ditched, delivered by a trap.
Make the girl thick and slab.
Add there to a tiger's chor'd run for the ingredients of our cold run.
Double, toil and sorrow.
Fire, burn and cold run, bubble.
Cool it with a baboon's blood, then the charm is firm and good.
Enter heckety.
Well done, I commend your pains and everyone shall share the gains.
And how about the cold run, sing? Like hills and fairies it ring.
And chanting all that you put in.
Music and a song. Black spirits, etc.
Exit heckety.
By the prickling of my thumbs, something wicked this way comes.
Open locks, whoever knocks.
Enter McBath.
How now you secret black and midnight haggs? What is it you do?
Addied without name.
I conjure you by that which you profess.
How air you come to know it, answer me.
Though you untie the winds and let them fight against the churches,
though the yesty waves can found in swallow navigation up,
though bladed corn be lodged and trees blown down,
though castles topple on their waters heads,
though palaces and pyramids do slope their heads to their foundations,
though the treasure of nature's Germans tumble all together,
even till destruction's sicken, answer me to what I ask you.
Speak, demand.
We'll answer.
Say, if the head is rather here it from our mouths,
or from our masters.
Call him.
Let me see him.
Pour in, south's blood, that have eaten a nine-faro,
grease that sweatin' from the murderous gibbet,
throw it to the flame.
Come, high all o'er, that self-an office,
deathly show thunder, first apparition and armed head.
Tell me they're one-on-power.
He knows life ought, here is speech, but say thou not,
Macbeth, Macbeth, Macbeth, beware Macduff,
beware the thane of five, dismiss me, enough.
He descends.
But here thou art for thy good caution, thanks.
Thou has hopped my fero right, but one would more.
He will not be commanded, here's another more potent than the first.
Thunder, second apparition, a bloody child.
Macbeth, Macbeth, Macbeth, Macbeth.
Had I three ears, I'd hear thee.
Be bloody, bold, and resolute.
Lapt to scorn the power of man for none of woman born shall harm Macbeth.
Decends.
Then live Macduff, what need I fear of thee, but yet I'll make a sure-and-stouble sure-and-take-a-bond-of-fate.
Thou shall not live, that I may tell pale-hearted fear it lies,
and sleep in spite of thunder.
Thunder, third apparition, a child crowned with a tree in his hand.
What is this that rises like the issue of a king, and wears upon his baby brow the round-and-top of sovereignty?
Listen, but speak not to it.
Be lying, metal, proud, and take no care who chaves, who frets, or where conspires are.
Macbeth shall never vanquished be until great Burnham would to hide Duns and Inhill shall come against him.
Decends.
That will never be. Who can impress the forest, bid the tree unfixes earthbound route.
Sweet boldments good. Rebellious dead rise never till the wood of Burnham rise,
and our high-pleased Macbeth shall live the leeks of nature pay his breath to time and mortal custom.
Yet my heart throbs to know one thing. Tell me if your heart can tell so much.
Shall bankers issue ever rain in this kingdom?
She too know no more.
I will be satisfied.
Dun I may this an eternal curse fall on you. Let me know why things that call it and what noise is this.
Hold boys.
Show. Show. Show. Show. Show is I, and Grease out come like shadows.
So depart.
A show of eight kings and bank will last king with a glass in his hand.
There are two like the spirit of bank will down by crown does see my eyelids and I hear.
Though other goldbound brow is like the first. A third is like the former.
Fear of they hags why do you show me this? A fourth.
Start eyes. But with the line straight up to the crack of doom. Another yet.
Our seventh I will see no more.
And yet the eighth appears. Who bears a glass which shows me many more.
And some I see that twofold balls and treble septice carry.
Horrible sight.
Now I see it is true. For the blood bolted bank will smiles upon me and points it for his.
What is this so?
I sir. All this is so. But why stands Macbeth thus amazingly.
Consisters cheer we up his sprites and show the best of our delights.
I'll charm the air to give a sound while you perform your antic round.
That this great king make Ingley say our duties did his welcome day.
Music the witches dance and vanish.
Where are they? Come? Let this pernicious hour stand I a cursive in the calendar.
Come in without there.
Enter Lennox.
What's your grace as will?
So you the weird sisters?
No my lord.
Came they not by you? No indeed my lord.
Infected be the air where on they ride and damned all those that trust them.
I did hear the galloping of horses who was came by.
His two or three my lord that bring you word Macbeth is fled to England.
Flight to England?
I'm a good lord.
Aside.
Time though anticipates my dread exploits. The flighty purpose never is or took unless the deed go with it.
From this moment the very first things of my heart shall be the first things of my hand.
And even now to crown my thoughts with acts be it thought and done.
The castle of Macduff.
I will surprise.
Seize upon five.
Give to the edge of the sword his wife, his babes and all unfortunate souls that trace him in his line.
No boasting like a fool.
This deed I'll do before the purpose cool.
But no more sights.
Where are these gentlemen? Come bring me where they are.
Exit.
Seen two Macduff's castle.
Enter Macduff's wife, her son and Ross.
What had he done to make him fly the land?
You must have patience madam.
He had none. His flight was madness.
What our actions do not are fears to make us traders.
You know not whether it was his wisdom or his fear.
Wisdom.
To leave his wife, to leave his babes, his mansion and his titles,
in a place from whens himself does fly?
He loves us not.
He wants the natural touch.
For the poor ran the most dominative of birds will fight her young ones in her nest against the owl.
All is the fear.
And nothing is the love.
As little as the wisdom where the flight so runs against all reasons,
my dearest cousin.
I pray you are school yourself.
But for your husband he is noble, wise, judicious and best knows the fits of the seasons.
I dare not speak much further.
But cruel other times when we are traders and do not know ourselves.
When we hold room of from what we fear.
Yet no not what we fear but float upon a wild and violent sea each way and move.
I take my leave of you.
She will not be long but I will be here again.
Things that the worst will see so as climb up what they were before.
My pretty cousin.
Blessing upon you.
Father he is and yet he is fatherless.
I am so much a fool.
Should I stay longer?
It would be my disgrace and your discomfort.
I take my leave at once.
Exit.
Sir, your father's dead.
And what will you do now?
How will you live?
As birds do mother.
What?
With worms and flies?
With what I get I mean and so do they.
Poor bird.
Does never fear the net nor lie the pitfall nor the gin?
Why should I mother?
Poor birds.
They are not set for.
My father is not dead for all you are saying.
Yes he is dead.
How will they do for a father?
No.
How will you do for a husband?
Why?
I could buy me 20 at any market.
Then you buy him to sell again.
The speaks with all thy wit.
And yet he faith with wind enough for thee.
Was my father a trader mother?
I that he was.
What is a trader?
Why?
One that swears and flies.
And be all traders that do so.
Everyone that does so is a trader and must be hanged.
And must they all be hanged that swear and lie?
Everyone.
Who must hang them?
Why?
The honest man.
Then the liars and swears are fools.
For there are liars and swears and no to beat the honest man and hang up them.
How God help thee poor monkey.
But how will thou do for a father?
If he were dead, you'd weak for him.
If you will not, it were a good sign that I could quickly have a new father.
Poor Bratler.
How thou darkest?
Enter a messenger.
Bless you, Feldem.
I am not known to you.
Though in your state of honor I am perfect.
I doubt some danger does approach you nearly if you will take a homely man's advice.
Be not found here.
Hence with your little ones to fright you thus may think I am too savage.
To do worse to you were felt cruelty, which is too naive person.
Heaven preserve you.
I dare abide no longer.
Exit, messenger.
Whether should I fly.
I have done no harm.
But I remember now I am in this earthly world where to do harm is often lovable.
To do good sometimes I count a dangerous folly.
Why then, unless do I put up that womanly defense to say I have done no harm?
What are these faces?
Enter murderers.
Where's your husband?
I hope in no place so unsangified were such as thou may find him.
He's a traitor.
Thou lieest thou shagyard villain?
What you egg?
Stubbing him.
Young fry of treachery.
He has killed me mother.
Run away.
I pray you.
Dies.
Exit Lady MacDuff crying murder followed by murderer.
Seen three, England, before the king's palace.
Enter Malcolm and MacDuff.
Let us seek out some desolate shade in their weeper set bosom's empty.
Let us rather hold fast the mortal sword and like good men best ride our downfall, birthed him.
Each new more new widows how, new orphans cry.
New sorrows strike heaven on the face that have resounds as if it felt with Scotland and Yelms.
Scotland and Yelmed out like syllable of dollar.
What I believe, I'll well.
What no believe and what I can redress.
As I shall find the time to friend I will.
What you have spoke and may be so perchance.
This tyrant who soul-named blisters our tongues was once thought honest.
You have loved him well. He has not touched you yet.
I am young but something you may deserve of him through me and wisdom to offer up a weak poor innocent lamb.
To peas and angry God.
I am not treacherous but my path is.
A good and virtuous nature may recoil in an imperial charge.
But I shall crave your pardon.
That which you are, my thoughts cannot transpose.
Angels are bright still though the brightest fell.
Though all things foul would wear the brows of grace.
Yet grace must still look so.
I have lost my hopes.
Pretends even there where I did find my doubts.
Why in that raunus left you wife in child those precious motives.
Those strong knots of love without leave taking.
I pray you.
Let not my jealousy be your dishonors.
But my own safeties.
You may be rightly just whatever I shall think.
Bleed, bleed poor country.
Great tyranny lay thou thy basis sure.
For goodness down I check thee.
Well thou thy wrongs.
The title is a feared.
Fair thee well Lord.
I would not be the villain that thou thinks.
For the whole space that's in the tyrants grasp and the rich east to boot.
Be not offended.
I speak not as an absolute fear of you.
I think our country sinks beneath the yoke.
It weeps it bleeds in each new day.
A gash is added to her wounds.
I think with all there would be hands uplifted in my right.
And here from gracious England have I offer of goodly thousands.
But for all this, when I shall tread upon the tyrants head or wear it on my side.
Yet my poor country shall have more vices than it had before.
More suffer and more sundry ways than ever.
By him that shall succeed.
What should he be?
It is my self I mean in whom I know all the particulars of vice so graffed.
That when they shall be opened, black Macbeth will seem as pure as snow.
And the poor state esteem him as a lamb being compared with my confineless arms.
Not in the legions of harrowed elk and come a devil more damned in even
to top Macbeth.
I grant him bloody legionious, avaricious, false, deceitful, sudden, malicious,
smacking of every sin that has a name.
But there's no bottom none in my voluptuousness.
Your wives, your daughters, your matrons and your maids could not fill up the
cistern of my lust and my desire all continent impediments would
or bear that did oppose my will.
Better Macbeth than such and one to reign.
Boudless in temperance in nature is a tyranny.
It has been the untimely emptying of the happy throne and fall of many kings.
But fear not yet to take upon you what is yours.
You may convey your pleasures in a spacious plenty and yet seem cold.
The time you may so hoodwink.
We have willing deems enough that cannot be that voucher in you to devour so many
as will to greatness dedicate themselves, finding it so inclined.
With this their grows in my most ill-composed affection such a stancheless
Everest that where I king I should cut off the nobles for their lands, desire his
jewels and this other's house and my more having would be as a
suss to make me hunger more that I should forge quarrels unjust against the
good and loyal destroying them for wealth.
This Everest sticks deeper, grows with more pernicious root than some
of the most unforeseen lust and it has been the sword of our slain kings.
Yet do not fear, Scotland hath foysens to fill up your will of your mirrown, all these are
portable with other graces wade.
But I have none.
The king becoming graces as justice, verity, temperance, stavleness,
bounty, perseverance, mercy, loneliness, devotion, patience, courage,
fortitude, I have no relish of them, but abound in the division of each
several crime, acting it many ways.
Nay had I power I should pour the sweet milk of concord into hell, uproar the
universal peace, confound all unity on earth.
Oh, Scotland, Scotland!
If such a one be fit to govern speak, I am as I have spoken.
Fit to govern, no, not to live, own nation miserable, with an unsightled,
tyrant bloody sceptored, when shall thou see thy wholesome days again, since that the
truest issue of thy throne, by his own introduction stands a curse, and as blasphemous
breed thy royal father was the most seated king, the queen the bore thee,
offender upon her knees than on her feet, died every day she lived, fair thee well.
These evils thou repeatest upon thy self have banished me from Scotland.
Oh, my breast thy whole bends here.
Make doth this noble passion, child of integrity, hath from my soul wiped the black
scruples, reconciled my thoughts to thy good truth and honor.
Devilish mech, Beth, by many of these trains, hath sought to win me into his power and
modest wisdom plucks me, from over credulous haste, but God above,
deal between thee and me. For even now I put myself to thy direction, an unspeaked
mind-owned detraction, here abdure the taints and blanes I laid upon myself, for strangers
to my nature I am yet unknown to woman, never was for sworn.
Scaresly have coveted what was my own, at no time broke my faith, would not betray the devil
to his fellow and delight no less in truth than life. My first false speaking was this
upon myself. What I am truly is thine and my poor countries to command, wither indeed before
thy hear approach, my seward with ten thousand warlike men, already at a point was setting
forth, now we'll together in the chance of goodness be like our warranted quarrel. Why are you silent?
Such welcome and unwelcome things at once, to his heart to reconcile.
Enter a doctor. Well, more and more, comes the king forth, I pray you.
I, sir, there are a crew of wretched souls that stay his cure. Their melody convinces the
great assay of art, but at his touch, such sanctity, have heaven given his hand they presently
amend. I thank you, doctor.
Exit, doctor. What's the disease he means?
To his call, the evil. A most miraculous work in this good king, which often since my hear remain in
England, I have seen him do. How he solicits heaven, himself best knows, but strangely visited
people all swan and ulcerous pitiful to the eye, the mere despair of surgery he cures, hanging a golden stamp
about their necks, put on with holy prayers and to his spoken, to the succeeding royalty he leaves the healing
action, with this strange virtue he had a heavenly gift of prophecy, and sundry blessings hang about his throne
that speak him full of grace. Enter Ross. See who comes here. My countrymen, but yet I know him not.
My ever-gettle cousin, welcome, Hither. I know him now, good God, be times remove the means that makes a strangers.
Sir, a men. Stands Scotland where it did.
Mass for country. Almost afraid to know itself. It cannot be called a mother, but a grave. Where nothing,
but who knows nothing is once seen to smile. Where size and groans and shrieks that rent the air are made,
not marked, where violent sorrow seems a modern ecstasy. The dead man's nell is their scarce asked for who.
And good men's lives expire before the flowers in their caps, dying or are they sicken.
Oh, relation to nice and yet too true. What's the newest grief?
That of a now-as-age, Darth Hiss, the speaker, each minute teams a new one. How does my wife?
Why well? And all my children? Well, too. The tyrant has not battered at their peace.
No, they were well at peace when I did leave him. Be not a negative of your speech, how goes?
When I came here to transport the tidings of which I have heavily born, there ran a rumor of many worthy fellows that were out,
which was to my belief, witness the rather for the race or the tyrants power of what? Now is the time of help.
Your eye in Scotland would create soldiers, make our women fight to tough their dire distresses.
Beat their comfort, we are coming thither. Gracious England, Hathlentus, could seeward and 10,000 men,
an older and a better soldier, none, that Christendom gives out.
What could I answer this comfort with the like? But I have words that would be hollowed out in the desert air.
Where hearing should not latch them. What concern, thee? The general cause,
or is it a fee grief, due to some single breast?
No mind that's honest, but in it shares some woe, though the main part pertains to you alone.
If it be mine, keep it not from me. Quickly let me have it.
Let not your ears despise my tongue forever, which shall possess them with the heaviest sound that ever yet they heard.
I guess at it. Your castle is surprised. Your wife and babe savagely slaughtered.
To relate the manner where, on the quarry of these murder dare to add the death of you.
Merciful heaven, what man, near pull your hat upon your brows, give sorrow words,
the grief that does not speak whisper as the or fraught heart and bids it break.
My children too. Wife, children, servants, all that could be found.
And I must be from then. My wife killed two. I have said.
Be comforted. Let's make us medicines of our great revenge to cure this deadly grief.
He has no children. All my pretty ones. Do you say all? Oh, hell, kite? All?
What all my pretty chickens under dam at one fell swoop disputed like a man?
I shall do so, but I must also feel it as a man. I cannot but remember such things were that were most precious to me.
Did heaven look on and would not take their pot?
Sinful Macduff, they were all struck for thee, not that I am, not for their own merits, but for mine fell slother on their souls.
Heaven rest them now. Be this the wheatstone of your sword. Let grief convert to anger, blunt, not the heart, in rage it.
Oh, I could play the woman with my eyes and brag it with my tongue, but jettle heavens cut short all into mission.
Front to front bring thou this feigned of Scotland and myself within my swords length, set him.
If he escaped, heaven forgive him too.
This time goes manly. Come go we to the king. Our power is ready. Our lack is nothing but our leave.
Macbeth is right for shaking and the powers above put on their instruments.
Receive what cheer you may, the night is long that never finds the day.
Exit.